Zhenya Kogan | 415.225.8630 | zhenya.kogan@gmail.com

Objective:

Front end web development position, full-time or contract.

Summary:

My strongest skills are within front end web development. I believe in clean code with cross browser compatibility and hacks only as a last resort. In all the jobs listed below my main responsibility has been front end with minor back end coding and debugging.

Skills:

Excellent HTML and CSS skills; proficient in JavaScript with jQuery and YUI toolkits, SVN and Git version control systems; working knowledge of XSLT, FBML, XUL, Freemarker, Django, Jinja, PHP, Shell, Python, Ruby on Rails, Flash; fluent in Vim and Photoshop editors.

Experience:

Contract Web Developer, 03/2008 — present

Peralta Informatics

Work in a small team of engineers. Responsible for HTML/CSS development in ASP.NET/XSLT environment. Design independently as well as contribute to revisions.

Varona
Yael Designs
Please Help Me Pay Off My House
Apply Video Solutions Google ads landing page

URMYStar

Develop new features and advance existing components using JavaScript with jQuery toolkit in PHP environment.

Togetherville

Helped resolve cross-browser issues and built new HTML templates for the stand-alone website and Facebook application. Worked in Ruby on Rails environment.

Rdio (startup in stealth mode), Web Developer, 12/2008 — 11/2009

HTML/CSS/JavaScript development of a large music distribution website built using the Django framework. Responsible for cross-browser compatibility. Occasionally debugged Flash objects and extended existing Python components.

AKQA, Web Developer, 12/2007 — 12/2008

HTML/CSS/JavaScript development of small to medium-sized ASP.NET/XSLT and Freemarker projects. Worked as a front end developer on a Facebook application using Facebook Markup Language. Contributed to the prototype of a marketing tool involving a client-provided content data store and a Mozilla Firefox extension using XUL.

The Lost Ring
Visa Business Network
Target Gift Registry
Method
Nike Store
Nike Basketball
Game Changers

Education:

University of California, Berkeley Studied Applied Mathematics with emphasis in Computer Science. 08/2001 — 01/2006